(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-11T20:17:53.199879",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you reside in this heart,
一人じゃないから
I'm not alone.
いつか描いた文字の中 目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺れた
Within words once drawn, the scenery shook with color when I closed my eyes.
少し戸惑う風の中 (響く)
Amidst the slightly bewildered wind... (resonating)
重なる花びら 私たちの声
Overlapping petals, our voices,
一瞬 一瞬 捕まえるみたいに
As if catching every single moment,
もっと もっと 踏み出せたら (we are one)
If we step forward more and more (we are one).
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて (繋げて)
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you reside in this heart,
強くなくてもいい (なくてもいい) 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong (it's okay), this present light,
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放す
With you and me, gathering everything, releasing it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから (その手で)
We'll gently make this miracle shine together (with those hands).
力が湧くから
Because strength wells up inside,
新たな種を握りしめ
Clenching new seeds tightly,
遠い未来へと強く願い込め撒いた
Wishing strongly and sowing them toward a distant future.
希望の風を吹かせて (泳ぐ)
Letting the wind of hope blow through (swimming).
理想の花びら祈る明日の空
Petals of ideals praying in tomorrow's sky,
何百 (何百) 億も (億も) 光る星みたいに
Like hundreds of millions of shining stars,
ずーっと (ずーっと) ずーっと終わらないから
Forever and ever, it will never end.
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて (抱きしめて)
This smile tightly embraces the past (embraces it).
今未来にこの手伸ばしてゆくから
Extending my hand into the future now,
時に転んでも (それでいい) 空を見上げよう
Even if I stumble at times (that's fine), let's look up at the sky.
笑い (泣いた) 日々を (すべて) 刻んでゆく
Carving out all the days of laughter and tears,
次の夢を掴み取るって約束するから (この手で)
Promising to seize our next dream (with these hands).
踏み出そう ここから
Let's take a step forward from here.
(we are with you we are with you) 同じ未来を見ていたい
(We are with you, we are with you) I want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
I want to hold that dream in my hands.
(we are with you capture the moment) 触れた奇跡の中で
(We are with you, capture the moment) Amidst the touched miracle,
その先まで続く空にまぎれたら 君の場所と今を繋ぎたくて
If I blend into the endless sky beyond, I want to connect your place with the present.
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて (繋げて)
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you reside in this heart,
強くなくてもいい (なくてもいい) 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong (it's okay), this present light,
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放す
With you and me, gathering everything, releasing it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから (この手で)
We'll gently make this miracle shine together (with these hands).
咲かせよう ここから (一緒に)
Let's make it bloom from here (together).
一人じゃないから (we are one)
Because we are not alone (we are one).
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you reside in this heart,
一人じゃないから
I'm not alone.
いつか描いた文字の中 目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺れた
Within words once drawn, the scenery shook with color when I closed my eyes.
少し戸惑う風の中 (響く)
Amidst the slightly bewildered wind... (resonating)
重なる花びら 私たちの声
Overlapping petals, our voices,
一瞬 一瞬 捕まえるみたいに
As if catching every single moment,
もっと もっと 踏み出せたら (we are one)
If we step forward more and more (we are one).
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて (繋げて)
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you reside in this heart,
強くなくてもいい (なくてもいい) 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong (it's okay), this present light,
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放す
With you and me, gathering everything, releasing it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから (その手で)
We'll gently make this miracle shine together (with that hand).
力が湧くから
Because strength wells up inside,
新たな種を握りしめ
Clenching new seeds tightly,
遠い未来へと強く願い込め撒いた
Wishing strongly and sowing them toward a distant future.
希望の風を吹かせて (泳ぐ)
Letting the wind of hope blow through (swimming).
理想の花びら祈る明日の空
Petals of ideals praying in tomorrow's sky,
何百 (何百) 億も (億も) 光る星みたいに
Like hundreds of millions of shining stars,
ずーっと (ずーっと) ずーっと終わらないから
Forever and ever, it will never end.
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて (抱きしめて)
This smile tightly embraces the past (embraces it).
今未来にこの手伸ばしてゆくから
Extending my hand into the future now,
時に転んでも (それでいい) 空を見上げよう
Even if I stumble at times (that's fine), let's look up at the sky.
笑い (泣いた) 日々を (すべて) 刻んでゆく
Carving out all the days of laughter and tears,
次の夢を掴み取るって約束するから (この手で)
Promising to seize our next dream (with these hands).
踏み出そう ここから
Let's take a step forward from here.
(we are with you we are with you) 同じ未来を見ていたい
(We are with you, we are with you) I want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
I want to hold that dream in my hands.
(we are with you capture the moment) 触れた奇跡の中で
(We are with you, capture the moment) Amidst the touched miracle,
その先まで続く空にまぎれたら 君の場所と今を繋ぎたくて
If I blend into the endless sky beyond, I want to connect your place with the present.
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて (繋げて)
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に君のカケラがあるから
Because fragments of you reside in this heart,
強くなくてもいい (なくてもいい) 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong (it's okay), this present light,
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放す
With you and me, gathering everything, releasing it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから (この手で)
We'll gently make this miracle shine together (with these hands).
咲かせよう ここから (一緒に)
Let's make it bloom from here (together).
一人じゃないから (we are one)
Because we are not alone (we are one).
あの涙が今の僕らを繋いで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に君のカケラがあるから
because a piece of you is in this heart,
一人じゃないから
because I am not alone.
いつか描いた文字の中
Within the words we once wrote,
目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺らいだ
the scenery that colors the space behind closed eyes swayed,
少し戸惑う風の中 (響く)
in a slightly bewildered wind (resounding),
重なる花びら 私たちの声
overlapping petals, our voices.
一瞬 (一瞬) 一瞬 (一瞬) 捕らえるみたいに
Like capturing every single fleeting moment,
もっと (もっと) もっと踏み出せたら 【we are one】
if we could step forward even more [we are one].
あの涙が今の僕らを繋いで (繋いで)
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に君のカケラがあるから
because a piece of you is in this heart,
強くなくてもいい (なくてもいい) 今の光を
it's okay not to be strong (it's okay), this light,
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放つ
gathering with you (everything) and releasing it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせる から (その手で) 力が湧くから
Because we will softly make this miracle shine (with those hands) as strength wells up.
新たな種を握りしめ
Clenching new seeds in our hands,
遠い未来へと強く願い込め撒いた
we sowed them with strong wishes toward a distant future.
希望の風を吹かせては (泳ぐ)
Letting the wind of hope blow (swimming),
理想の花びら 祈る明日の空
ideal petals, praying to tomorrow's sky.
何百 (何百) 億も (億も) 光る星みたいに
Like hundreds (hundreds) of billions (billions) of shining stars,
ずっと (ずっと) ずっと終わらないから
it will never, ever end.
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて (抱きしめて)
This smile tightly embraces the past (embraces it),
今未来にこの手伸ばしてゆく から
so I'll keep reaching out this hand toward the future now.
時に転んでも (それでいい) 空を見上げよう
Even if I stumble sometimes (that's fine), let's look up at the sky.
笑い (泣いた) 日々を (すべて) 刻んでゆく
Etching away all the days we laughed (and cried).
次の夢を掴み取るって約束するから (この手で) 踏み出そう ここから
Promising to seize our next dream, let's step forward (with these hands) from here.
(we are with you)
同じ未来を見ていたい あの夢手ニしたい
I want to see the same future, I want to make that dream mine.
(we are with you, capture the moment)
触れた奇跡の中で
Within the miracle we touched,
その先まで続く空にまぎれたら
if we blend into the sky extending beyond,
君の場所と今を繋ぎたくて
I want to connect your place and the present.
あの涙が今の僕らを繋いで (繋いで)
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に君のカケラがあるから
because a piece of you is in this heart,
強くなくてもいい (なくてもいい) 今の光を
it's okay not to be strong (it's okay), this light,
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放つ
gathering with you (everything) and releasing it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせる から (この手で) 咲かせよう ここから (一緒に)
Because we will softly make this miracle shine (with these hands) let's make it bloom from here (together).
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we are not alone [we are one].
あの涙が今の僕らを繋いで
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に君のカケラがあるから
because a piece of you is in this heart,
一人じゃないから
because I am not alone.
いつか描いた文字の中
Within the words we once wrote,
目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺らいだ
the scenery that colors the space behind closed eyes swayed,
少し戸惑う風の中 (響く)
in a slightly bewildered wind (resounding),
重なる花びら 私たちの声
overlapping petals, our voices.
一瞬 (一瞬) 一瞬 (一瞬) 捕らえるみたいに
Like capturing every single fleeting moment,
もっと (もっと) もっと踏み出せたら 【we are one】
if we could step forward even more [we are one].
あの涙が今の僕らを繋いで (繋いで)
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に君のカケラがあるから
because a piece of you is in this heart,
強くなくてもいい (なくてもいい) 今の光を
it's okay not to be strong (it's okay), this light,
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放つ
gathering with you (everything) and releasing it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせる から (その手で) 力が湧くから
Because we will softly make this miracle shine (with those hands) as strength wells up.
新たな種を握りしめ
Clenching new seeds in our hands,
遠い未来へと強く願い込め撒いた
we sowed them with strong wishes toward a distant future.
希望の風を吹かせては (泳ぐ)
Letting the wind of hope blow (swimming),
理想の花びら 祈る明日の空
ideal petals, praying to tomorrow's sky.
何百 (何百) 億も (億も) 光る星みたいに
Like hundreds (hundreds) of billions (billions) of shining stars,
ずっと (ずっと) ずっと終わらないから
it will never, ever end.
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて (抱きしめて)
This smile tightly embraces the past (embraces it),
今未来にこの手伸ばしてゆく から
so I'll keep reaching out this hand toward the future now.
時に転んでも (それでいい) 空を見上げよう
Even if I stumble sometimes (that's fine), let's look up at the sky.
笑い (泣いた) 日々を (すべて) 刻んでゆく
Etching away all the days we laughed (and cried).
次の夢を掴み取るって約束するから (この手で) 踏み出そう ここから
Promising to seize our next dream, let's step forward (with these hands) from here.
(we are with you)
同じ未来を見ていたい あの夢手にしたい
I want to see the same future, I want to make that dream mine.
(we are with you, capture the moment)
触れた奇跡の中で
Within the miracle we touched,
その先まで続く空にまぎれたら
if we blend into the sky extending beyond,
君の場所と今を繋ぎたくて
I want to connect your place and the present.
あの涙が今の僕らを繋いで (繋いで)
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に君のカケラがあるから
because a piece of you is in this heart,
強くなくてもいい (なくてもいい) 今の光を
it's okay not to be strong (it's okay), this light,
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放つ
gathering with you (everything) and releasing it to the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせる から (この手で) 咲かせよう ここから (一緒に)
Because we will softly make this miracle shine (with these hands) let's make it bloom from here (together).
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we are not alone [we are one].
ドンジャラなどたくさんの商品が発売いたします！
Donjara and many other items are now on sale!
会場限定でプレゼント！
A venue-exclusive gift!
バンダイブース・バンダイスピリッツブースでは会場限定グッズも無料配布中！
Free venue-exclusive merch at the Bandai & Bandai Spirits booths!
プレバンではすぐに使えるクーポンももらえるチャンス！
Plus a chance to get coupons usable right away on Premium Bandai!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiß Schwarz!
楽しむ準備はいい？
Are you ready to have fun?
ヴァイスシュヴァルツの舞台でも青春しよう！
Let's enjoy our youth on the Weiß Schwarz stage too!
プレミアムブースター ホロライブプロダクション Summer Collection 3月22日発売
Summer Collection releasing March 22nd!
ホロスターズが
HOLOSTARS is...
ヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウに登場！
...now in Weiß Schwarz Blau!
ようこそカードゲームの舞台へ！
Welcome to the card game stage!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウ スタートデッキ＆ブースターパック ホロスターズ 好評発売中
Start Decks & Booster Packs for HOLOSTARS on sale now!
hololive SUPER EXPO 2024開催を記念してホロライブメンバーのねんどろいどが新衣装になって再登場！
Hololive Nendoroids return in new outfits for SUPER EXPO 2024!
新しいねんどろいどをお楽しみに！
Look forward to the new Nendoroids!
フリューからホロライブプライズが全国アミューズメント施設に
Hololive prizes from FuRyu coming to amusements nationwide!
2024年7月以降に続々登場！
Releasing sequentially starting July 2024!
今後国内のホロライブメンバー全員展開予定！
All domestic Hololive members scheduled to be featured!
最新情報はキャラ広場 ホロライブで検索
Search 'Chara Hiroba Hololive' for the latest info!
さざめく街の喧騒
The bustling noise of the city
掻き消すように弦を弾いて
Strumming the strings to drown it out
一心不乱に叫ぶ午後
An afternoon of shouting single-mindedly
割れた爪を眺めてる暇もないよ
With no time even to gaze at chipped nails
時の流れに呑み込まれたっていい
It's fine if we get swallowed by the flow of time
6月などたくさんの商品が発売いたします！
Many products, including June releases, will be released!
バンダイ／BANDAI SPIRITSブースでは、会場限定グッズも無料配布中！
At the Bandai / BANDAI SPIRITS booth, venue-exclusive goods are also being distributed for free!
プレバンではすぐに使えるクーポンももらえるチャンス！
Don't miss your chance to get instant-use coupons on Premium Bandai!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Weiss Schwarz!
楽しむ準備はいい？
Are you ready to have fun?
ヴァイスシュヴァルツの舞台でも青春しよう！
Let's experience youth on the Weiss Schwarz stage too!
収集しよう！
Let's collect them!
プレミアムブースター ホロライブプロダクション Summer Collection 3月22日(金)発売！
Premium Booster Hololive Production Summer Collection releases Friday, March 22nd!
ホロスターズが
HOLOSTARS is
ヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウに登場！
making its debut in Weiss Schwarz Blau!
ようこそカードゲームの舞台へ！
Welcome to the card game stage!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツブラウ
Weiss Schwarz Blau
スタートデッキ＆ブースターパック ホロスターズ 好評発売中！
Start Decks & Booster Packs for HOLOSTARS are on sale now!
ホロライブメンバーのねんどろいどが新衣装になって再登場！
Hololive members' Nendoroids return in brand-new outfits!
新しいねんどろいどをお楽しみに！
Look forward to the new Nendoroids!
フリューから「ホロライブ」プライズが
"Hololive" prizes from FuRyu
全国アミューズメント施設に2024年7月以降に続々登場！
will be arriving sequentially in amusement facilities nationwide starting July 2024!
今後国内のホロライブメンバー全員展開予定！
All domestic Hololive members are scheduled to be featured in the future!
推しの曲、めっちゃいいよね！
Your oshi's song is so good, right?
みるハコでチャンス！
Take the chance with Miruhako!
みるハコなら臨場感たっぷりで推しのコンテンツが楽しめる！
With Miruhako, you can fully enjoy your oshi's content with immersive realism!
みるハコ最高！推し活も増やそう、みるハコ！
Miruhako is the best! Boost your oshi activities with Miruhako!
予約受付中！5月31日(金)
Reservations open now until Friday, May 31st!
ReGLOSS 2nd Single「シンメトリー」 Digital Release 2024.03.24(SUN) 0:00
ReGLOSS 2nd Single "Symmetry" Digital Release 2024.03.24 (SUN) 0:00
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて
Those tears connect us right now,
この心に君のカケラがいるから
because fragments of you remain in this heart.
一人じゃないから
Because we are not alone,
いつか描いた文字の中
inside the words we once drew,
目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺れた
the coloring scenery swayed beyond closed eyes.
少し戸惑う風の中
In a slightly hesitant wind,
(響く) 重なる花びら
overlapping petals resound—
私たちの声
our voices.
一瞬一瞬捕らえるみたいに
As if capturing every single moment,
もっともっともっと踏み出せたなら
if we could step forward more and more,
【we are one】
[We are one]
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて (繋げて)
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に君のカケラがいるから
because fragments of you remain in this heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong, gathering today's light
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放つ
with me (and you), gathering (everything) and releasing it into the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
Because we will gently make this miracle shine,
(その手で) 力が湧くから 新たな種を握りしめ
strength wells up, gripping a new seed,
遠い未来へと強く願い込め撒いた
scattering it with strong wishes toward a distant future.
希望の風を吹かせは (泳ぐ)
Letting the wind of hope blow (swimming),
理想の花びら 祈る明日の空
ideal petals, praying for tomorrow's sky.
何百 (何百) 億も (億も) 輝く星みたいに
Like hundreds of (hundreds of) billions of (billions of) shining stars,
ずっと (ずっと) ずっと 終わらないから
forever (forever) forever, it will never end,
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて (抱きしめて)
this smile strongly embracing the past (embracing it),
今 未来にこの手伸ばしてゆくから
extending this hand toward the future now.
時には転んでも (それでいい) 空を見上げよう
Even if we stumble sometimes (that's fine), let's look up at the sky,
笑い (泣いた) 日々を (すべて) 刻んでゆく
carving out the days we laughed (and cried) (everything).
次の夢を掴み取るって約束するから (この手で)
Promising to grasp the next dream (with these hands),
踏み出そう ここから
let's step forward from here.
(we are with you we are with you)
同じ未来を見ていたい あの夢手にしたい
I want to see the same future, I want that dream in my hands.
(we are with you capture the moment)
触れた奇跡の中で その先まで続く空にまぎれたら
Wrapped in the touched miracle, blending into the sky that continues beyond,
君の場所と今をつなぎたくて
I wanted to connect your place and the present.
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて (繋げて)
Those tears connect us right now (connect us),
この心に君のカケラがいるから
because fragments of you remain in this heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong, gathering today's light
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放つ
with me (and you), gathering (everything) and releasing it into the sky.
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから (この手で)
Because we will gently make this miracle shine (with these hands),
咲かせよう ここから (一緒に)
let's make it bloom from here (together).
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we are not alone [We are one]
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて
Those tears of the past connect us now,
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you remain in my heart.
一人じゃないから
Because I'm not alone,
いつか描いた文字の中
Inside the letters I once drew...
目を閉じた先に色づく景色が揺れた
The scenery came alive beyond closed eyes,
少し戸惑う風の中 (響く)
trembling in the slightly hesitating wind.
重なる花びら 私たちの声
Overlapping petal fragments, our voices!
一瞬 一瞬 捕らえるみたいに
Capturing every single fleeting moment,
もっと もっと もっと 踏み出せたら 【we are one】
we take another step forward! [We are one]
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて (繋げて)
Those tears of the past connect us now (connect us),
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you remain in my heart.
強くなくてもいい (なくてもいい) 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong, let's gather this light
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放つ
together with you and release it to the sky!
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから (その手で)
We will make this miracle gently shine (with these hands),
力が湧くから
strength wells up inside,
新たな種を握りしめ
grasping a brand-new seed,
遠い未来へと強く願い込め蒔いたの
I sowed it with strong prayers toward a distant future.
希望の風を吹かせては (泳ぐ)
Let the winds of hope blow (swimming),
理想の花びら 祈る明日の空
ideal petals praying for tomorrow's sky.
何百 (何百) 億も (億も) 光る星みたいに
Like hundreds of millions of shining stars,
ずっと (ずっと) ずっと 終わらないから
forever and ever, it will never end,
この笑顔が過去を強く抱きしめて (抱きしめて)
this smile tightly embraces the past (embraces it)
今未来にこの手伸ばしてゆくから
and reaches out toward the future now.
時に転んでも (それでいい) 空を見上げようよ
Even if we stumble sometimes (that's alright),
笑い (泣いた) 日々を (すべて) 刻んでゆく
let's carve out our smiling (and weeping) days together!
次の夢を掴み取るって約束するから (この手で)
Promising to grasp our next dream with these hands,
踏み出そう ここから
let's take a step forward from here!
(we are with you we are with you)
同じ未来を見 ていたい あの夢 手にしたい
I want to see the same future, I want to make that dream mine.
(we are with you capture the moment)
触れた奇跡の中で
Caught in the midst of a touching miracle,
その先まで続く空にまぎれたなら
if we get swept away into the sky that extends beyond,
君の場所と今を繋げたくて
I want to connect your place and the present.
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて (繋げて)
Those tears of the past connect us now (connect us),
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you remain in my heart.
強くなくてもいい (なくてもいい) 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong, let's gather this light
僕と (君と) 集め (すべて) 空に放つ
together with you and release it to the sky!
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから (この手で)
We will make this miracle gently shine with these hands,
咲かせよう ここから (一緒に)
let's make it bloom from here, together!
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we are not alone. [We are one]
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて
Those tears of the past connect us now,
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you remain in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong, let's gather this light
僕と 集め 空に放つ
together with you and release it to the sky!
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We will make this miracle gently shine with these hands,
咲かせよう ここから 一緒に
let's make it bloom from here, together!
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we are not alone. [We are one]
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて
Those tears of the past connect us now,
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you remain in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong, let's gather this light
僕と 集め 空に放つ
together with you and release it to the sky!
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We will make this miracle gently shine with these hands,
咲かせよう ここから 一緒に
let's make it bloom from here, together!
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we are not alone. [We are one]
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて
Those tears of the past connect us now,
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you remain in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong, let's gather this light
僕と 集め 空に放つ
together with you and release it to the sky!
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We will make this miracle gently shine with these hands,
咲かせよう ここから 一緒に
let's make it bloom from here, together!
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we are not alone. [We are one]
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて
Those tears of the past connect us now,
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you remain in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong, let's gather this light
僕と 集め 空に放つ
together with you and release it to the sky!
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We will make this miracle gently shine with these hands,
咲かせよう ここから 一緒に
let's make it bloom from here, together!
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we are not alone. [We are one]
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて
Those tears of the past connect us now,
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you remain in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong, let's gather this light
僕と 集め 空に放つ
together with you and release it to the sky!
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We will make this miracle gently shine with these hands,
咲かせよう ここから 一緒に
let's make it bloom from here, together!
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we are not alone. [We are one]
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて
Those tears of the past connect us now,
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you remain in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を
It's okay not to be strong, let's gather this light
僕と 集め 空に放つ
together with you and release it to the sky!
この奇跡を僕らでそっと輝かせるから
We will make this miracle gently shine with these hands,
咲かせよう ここから 一緒に
let's make it bloom from here, together!
一人じゃないから 【we are one】
Because we are not alone. [We are one]
あの涙が今の僕らを繋げて
Those tears of the past connect us now,
この心に君の欠片がいるから
because pieces of you remain in my heart.
強くなくてもいい 今の光を…
It's okay not to be strong, let's gather this light...
hololive 5th fes. -DAY2-
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキッスで”
My repayment is "a kiss blown with all my love"!
きのせいじゃない 目は合ってるよ
It's not my imagination, our eyes are meeting!
♡作って恋にしちゃってください！
Make a heart and fall in love with me!
やれること 何でもします
I'll do whatever it takes!
NGなしで体当たり挑戦
Taking on challenges head-on with no restrictions!
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
Finding haters' comments through ego-searching...
ぶざけんな…！誰より分かってるし
"Don't mess with me...!" I know that better than anyone,
でも大丈夫 ステージに立てばみんながいる
but it's okay, when I stand on stage everyone is here.
行くよ！
Let's go!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキッスで”
My repayment is "a kiss blown with all my love"!
誑かすの！？もっと！夢を見せるの！？もっと！
Bewitching them?! More! Showing dreams?! More!
楽しんでて 愛の込めたスペシャルナイト
Have fun, a special night filled with love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you fan service!
お手紙も書いてください！ 何度も読んで宝物にします
Please write me letters too! I'll read them over and over and treasure them.
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
A scandal? It's still too early for that,
裏切りません！宣言しときます
but I won't betray you! I declare that right now.
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment,
ぶざけんな！実力で勝ってやる
"Don't mess with me!" I'll win with pure ability!
だからやらない 負けず嫌い私はいる
That's why I won't quit, the sore loser in me is still here.
行くよ！
Let's go!
拳上げて！もっと！汗をかいて！もっと！
Raise your fists! More! Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めたmonaビームで”
My repayment is "with a love-infused mona beam"!
大歓声！もっと！まだまだ！ねえ？もっと！
Loud cheers! More! Still more! Hey? More!
受け止めてね 愛の込めたわがままソング
Please accept my selfish song filled with love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you fan service!
はぁ… 終わりが近づく 寂しいね
Ah... the end is drawing near, it's lonely.
楽しいのに 泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying.
次も 次も また会えるよね？
We'll meet again and again, right?
約束！
Promise!
優しさに満ちている言葉も 心ない誰かの言葉さえも
Words filled with kindness, and even the heartless words of someone...
必要なんだ 必要なんだ 強くならろう
They're necessary, they're necessary, I'll grow stronger!
好きに叫べ！もっと！楽しんだもん勝ち！もっと！
Shout out your love! More! Those who enjoy win! More!
忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, so that this becomes a special day,
共に歌おう ずっと！ 共に歩もう ずっと！
Let's sing together forever! Let's walk together forever!
合言葉は とびっきり の l・o・v・e
Our passphrase is a sparkling L-O-V-E!
行くよ！
Let's go!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキッスで”
My repayment is "a kiss blown with all my love"!
誑かすの！？もっと！夢を見せるの！？もっと！
Bewitching them?! More! Showing dreams?! More!
楽しんでて 愛の込めたスペシャルナイト
Have fun, a special night filled with love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you fan service!
お手紙も書いてください！ 何度も読んで宝物にします
Please write me letters too! I'll read them over and over and treasure them.
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
A scandal? It's still too early for that,
裏切りません！宣言しときます
but I won't betray you! I declare that right now.
嫉妬、嫌がらせには負けない
I won't lose to jealousy or harassment,
ぶざけんな！実力で勝ってやる
"Don't mess with me!" I'll win with pure ability!
だからやめない 負けず嫌い私はいる
That's why I won't quit, the sore loser in me is still here.
行くよ！
Let's go!
拳上げて！もっと！汗をかいて！もっと！
Raise your fists! More! Work up a sweat! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めたmonaビームで”
My repayment is "with a love-infused mona beam"!
大歓声！もっと！まだまだ！ねえ？もっと！
Loud cheers! More! Still more! Hey? More!
受け止めてね 愛の込めたわがままソング
Please accept my selfish song filled with love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you fan service!
まだまだね！もっと！
Still more! More!
大歓声！もっと！
Loud cheers! More!
まだまだで！もっと！
Still more! More!
届け届けてね！
Deliver it, deliver it!
愛のこもったわがままソング
A selfish song filled with love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you fan service!
はぁ… 終わりが近づく 寂しいね
Ah... the end is drawing near, it's lonely.
楽しいのに 泣きそうだよ
Even though it's fun, I feel like crying.
次も 次も また会えるよね？
We'll meet again and again, right?
約束！
Promise!
優しさに満ちている言葉も
Words filled with kindness...
心ない誰かの言葉さえも
and even the heartless words of someone...
必要なんだ 必要なんだ 強くならろう
They're necessary, they're necessary, I'll grow stronger!
好きに叫べ！もっと！
Shout out your love! More!
楽しんだもん勝ち！もっと！
Those who enjoy win! More!
忘れないで 特別な日になりますように
Don't forget, so that this becomes a special day,
共に歌おう ずっと！ 共に歩もう ずっと！
Let's sing together forever! Let's walk together forever!
合言葉は とびっきり の l・o・v・e
Our passphrase is a sparkling L-O-V-E!
行くよ！
Let's go!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Fall in love with me! More! Look at me! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキッスで”
My repayment is "a kiss blown with all my love"!
誑かすの！？もっと！夢を見せるの！？もっと！
Bewitching them?! More! Showing dreams?! More!
楽しんでて 愛の込めたスペシャルナイト
Have fun, a special night filled with love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give you fan service!
位置について よいdon！って
Position, ready, set, go!
はりきってっちゃって かっと走って ちょっと待ってって
Full of enthusiasm, rushing ahead, wait a second!
しょうぜん こうぜん もうぜんぜん
Righteous, proper, totally completely,
なんないって まいいっちゅうかんない don't mind!
It's not happening, whatever, don't mind!
最初が大事 飛ばしすぎて
The start is important, flying too fast,
行き過ぎちゃって すっ転んで たって 参ってって
Going too far, tripping over, falling, giving up,
これじゃだめだ、だめだめだ
This is no good, no good at all,
神様助けてちょうだい oh yeah!
God, please help me, oh yeah!
馬鹿みたいに 流されちゃって
Swept away like a fool,
気づかなくて three, two, one で理解！
Without realizing, understand at three, two, one!
あれれ、まさかまされた！？
Huh, did I just get tricked?!
なんか思ってた予定と違うぞ
It's different from what I planned,
こんなはずじゃなかったなんて
It wasn't supposed to be like this,
焦ったのはほんのいっちゅうしんだけ
I was only flustered for a split second.
これはこれで楽しげな
This in itself is a fun,
スクールライフが待ってそうじゅうん？
School life waiting for us, right?
退屈とか単調なんて
Boredom and monotony,
ワードはほど遠い
Are miles away from these words,
きっと色あせない
Surely, an unfading,
物語が始まってしまう予感！
Premonition that a story is about to begin!
放課後ストライド なんてったって
After-school stride, no matter what,
やりたいようにやっちゃってって
Do it however you want to,
link ring link やがて ring link につながる
Link ring link, soon connecting to ring link,
愉快にほら ラッタってた
Happily, look, rat-a-tat,
熱に浮かされ あっちゅうっちゅうっちゅうあ
Floating in the heat, rat-a-tat-tat-tat,
green green green シグナルの示すままに
Green green green, as the signal shows,
いまを走り続けるのだ だだだ！
Continuing to run through the present, run!
皆さん！直席！
Everyone, assigned seats!
1回座りましょう！一旦座ってください！
Sit down once! Please sit down!
よしよしよし、いいですよ。
All right, all right, good.
いいお返事ですよ。
Good response.
さあ、皆さん、座りましたかね？
Well everyone, did you sit down?
今日はホロハニフェスだね。
Today is the HoloHani Fest.
では、行きますよ。全力正座と、起立！
Well then, here we go. Full-effort seiza and stand up!
気をつければ？
Watch out?
先生、おはようございます！
Teacher, good morning!
おはよう！ よくできました。
Good morning! Well done.
座れ、座れ。
Sit down, sit down.
ということでね、ファンサ歌ったね？
With that said, you sang the fansa song?
あ、そうなの先生、ファンサ歌ったね？
Ah, is that so, teacher, you sang fansa?
はい、ファンサを歌わせていただきました。
Yes, I got to sing Fansa.
めちゃ緊張した！緊張したの？
I was so nervous! Were you nervous?
歌う子なので、はい。
Because I'm a singer, yes.
でも、あの先生から見たら、ふぶき君は全然ファンサができてなかった。
But, from the teacher's perspective, Fubuki wasn't doing fansa at all.
え！？なので…
Eh!? That's why...
ちょっと反省したほうがいいと思う。
I think you should reflect a bit.
「気にしてさしちゃうから」って言ったの、なるほどって思ってまた足りないから、
"Because I'll make you care" - I thought that made sense, but it's still not enough.
ちょっと今ファンサしといたほうがいいと思う。え？いいですか？
I think you should do some fansa right now. Eh? Is that okay?
ほらほらほら！やった！
Hey hey hey! Yay!
じゃあ何する？
Then what will you do?
え、じゃあやっぱり、ふぶき、これライブで言ったら、あの、コール＆レスポンスじゃないですか、先生。
Well, if you say this at a live concert, isn't it a call and response, teacher?
そうだな。
That's right.
え、いいですか？皆さんもいいですか？やってくれました？
Eh, is that okay? Is everyone okay? Did you do it?
やったー！じゃあ、じゃあ、どうしようかな、どうしようかな？
Yay! Then, what should I do?
えーと、じゃあ、白上は、コンコンキーツって言って、みんなでねえって言ってください。
Uhm, then, Shirakami will say "Kon-kon-key-tsu", and everyone please say "Neh".
いいね。ねえだけ言う感じね。そう、ねえだけ言ってほしい。えーす！
Sounds good. Just saying "neh". Ace!
みんな、いいですかー？
Everyone, are you ready?
はい！今日の前途の皆さん優しいな。
Yes! Today's students are so kind.
いいね。ね、じゃあ行きますよ。
Nice. Well then, here we go.
コンコンキーツー！
Kon-kon-key-tsu!
ねえー！
Neh!
やったー！やったやった！おめでとうおめでとう！
Yay! Yay yay! Congrats congrats!
ま、ありがとうございます！これがファンサや。
Well, thank you! This is fansa.
これがファンサ！あ、そうや。
This is fansa! Ah, that's right.
よかったです！
I'm glad!
先生も、どうですか？え、先生もいいの？先生もぜひやってほしい。
Teacher, how about you? Eh, teacher, please definitely do it.
先生もいいの？
Teacher, is that okay?
うん、やって！
Yeah, do it!
あ、やったー！移動しますか、先生？
Ah, yay! Shall we move, teacher?
え、そしたら、じゃあ先生は、
Eh, in that case, teacher will...
「ゆびゆび」って言いたいから、え、先生が「ゆ」を担当するから、「び」、えっと、だから「ゆ」「び」「ゆ」「び」ってことだよ。わかる？
Teacher is in charge of "yu", and "bi", so "yu-bi-yu-bi". You understand?
先生、いける？
Teacher, can you do it?
コーワクすんじゃねえよ、生徒たち！
Don't get scared, students!
やれ、ちゃんと！
Do it properly!
皆さん行けますよね？いけるよね？
Everyone can do it, right? You can do it, right?
やるぞやるぞ、行くぞ！
Let's do it, let's go!
せーの、ゆ！び！ゆ！び！
Ready, yu! bi! yu! bi!
やったー！やったー！満足満足、ありがとうございます！
Yay! Yay! Satisfied, thank you very much!
ということで、ハニーワックスかけるホロライブ、始まりましたね！
Hololive covering HoneyWorks songs has started!
始まっちゃったね！始まりましたよ、マジで。
It has started! It really has started.
いや、ちょっと、まずはハニーワックスから歌わせていただきまして。
Well, first of all, we got to sing HoneyWorks songs.
かわいかったぞ。
You guys were cute.
いや、よかったです！先生のさ、曲もさ、めちゃめちゃ可愛いじゃないですか。
Well, I'm glad! Teacher's song is also super cute, isn't it?
MV見たら、みんな可愛かったですよね！
If you look at the MV, everyone was so cute!
ほら！いや、ありがとありがと！
Hey! Well, thanks thanks!
先生も頑張ったからな。
Because teacher worked hard too.
生徒には分けられないからな。さすがですね。
Can't share it with students. As expected.
そうだよ。ホロハニの唯一の、ね、先生ですからね。
That's right. Because I'm Holohani's only teacher, right.
そうだよ、先生だってね、制服着たかったんだからね！
That's right, teacher wanted to wear a uniform too!
着たかったんだから。着たかったら…
Wanted to wear it. If you wanted to...
白上だって、ちょっと先生やってみたかったんです。あ、本当に？
Shirakami wanted to try being a teacher a bit. Ah, really?
うん、なんか、いいじゃないですか、ちょっと。あ、それは無理やな、でも。
Yeah, like, wouldn't it be nice? Ah, that's impossible though.
なんでもう早く来ちゃったからな。
Because I arrived too early.
来ちゃったんだからな。
Because I arrived.
白上の先生もいいと思う人、いますか？やった！
Anyone who thinks Shirakami's teacher persona is good? Yay!
まあ、でもな、それはな。でも、ふぶきちゃんの先生はいいと思うよ。
Well, but, that's... But, I think Fubuki's teacher is good.
とかいいですか？
Is that okay?
...先生 先生みたいなこと
...sensei, something like a sensei...
先生みたいなこと？ ああ ええ、なんですかね？
Sensei-like? Ah, eh, what is it?
なんだろう？
I wonder what it is.
ちょっとじゃあ逆に、先生生徒として、
Let's try doing it backwards, as teacher and student.
気をつけて挨拶をしてみて下さい。
Try greeting me properly.
今日、気持ちよくなりたい。
I want to feel good.
で、先生、おはようございます。
And, "Sensei, ohayougozaimasu."
あ、そうね。
Ah, yes, right.
じゃあみんな、もう一回...
Then everyone, one more time...
起立って言おうかなって思ったら起立なんだよ。
Not "kiritsu", right?
起立なんだよ。ほい。
That's right.
ええ？
Eh?
うん。
Un.
あ、みんなおはよ。じゃあ、先生に挨拶しようか。
Ah, "Minna ohayou. Then, let's greet sensei."
起立！
"Kiritsu!"
うん。
Un.
ごめんね、何回も。
Sorry, how many times?
えー、気をつけて、礼！
Eh, "Kiyotsuke," "Rei."
違う違う違う違う違う！
Wrong, wrong, wrong, wrong.
座って。あっ、ど、どうだったっけ？
"Suwatte." Ah, wait, how was it?
おはようございます。ちょ、待って待って待って！
"Ohayougozaimasu," wait, wait, wait, wait.
え、でもみんなもこうね「おはようございます」って言うから、もう一回言ってくれる？ ごめんね。
Eh, everyone will say "Ohayougozaimasu," so can you say it again? Sorry.
いや、意味わかんないんだこのMC、どうなっとるんやこれ。
I don't get what this MC is, how does this work?
行くよ。おはようございます！
Let's go. "Ohayougozaimasu."
着席。
Chakusaku.
先生、おはようございます。
Sensei, ohayougozaimasu.
おはようございます。
Ohayougozaimasu.
みんなが気をつけてる間にもね、2分ぐらい経ってんだよ、先生。
While Korone-kun was doing that, two minutes have passed, sensei.
先生、ちょっとチャシップいません？ちょっとよく分からなくて。
Sensei, did you say "Chakusip"? I didn't get it.
すいませんでした。
Sorry.
I was sorry.
じゃあね、挨拶のこと、やっぱ先生向いてますね、みんなに。
Well, the greeting thing, sensei fits everyone, right?
確かに、そうだな。
That's right, that's right.
はい。
Yeah.
ということでね、
So, with that said...
ちょっと次の曲がなんか、実は先生の曲…
The next song is actually sensei's song...
え、先生もうやっちゃうの？ そう、ラズバー！
Eh, sensei, are you going to sing it too? "That's right!"
先生、コラボ楽曲名何でしたっけ？
Sensei, what was your guest track?
「かわいこチェック」だで。かわいこチェック！
"Kawaiko Check" was it? "Kawaiko Check!"
ということは、ちょっとね、ば、先生、
That means, wait, sensei.
あ、「かわいこ」先にチェックしといたほうが。
Ah, "Kawaiko," we should check that first.
そう、ちょっとここの会場に来てるみんなの中の「かわいこちゃん」に、
Let's check the venue.
「やっほー！」
"Yaho!"
あ、待ってよ。
Ah, wait, wait.
便秘さん、便秘さん、1つ飛ばして便秘さんやな。
Constipated person, constipation person, skip one and constipation person, right?
待って待って待って待って。
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
あ、よく見たら便秘さんやな。
Ah, if you look closely, they are constipation persons.
「よく見たら」って、さっき、
"If you look closely," didn't you just say it?
「2回目じゃないですか」
"Isn't that right?"
みんな可愛いよ、みんな可愛いよ。
"Everyone is cute, everyone is cute."
1つ飛ばして可愛いよ。
Skip one and everyone is cute.
飛ばすな、飛ばすな！
They are flying away, flying away!
あ、待って1、1を入れ忘れちゃった。
Wait, wait, I switched 1 and 2.
まあ、いいんじゃない？右さん、左さん、左右、左右、左右に。
It's fine, right? Left and right, left and right, right?
あーい！
Right!
ということで、じゃあじゃあじゃあ、
So, then, then, then...
かわいこチェック行きますかね？
Shall we go check if they're cute?
じゃあ最後に、もう一回やときますか、やっぱり。
Then should we do it one more time at the end, after all?
なにを？
What?
最後の締めと言ったら気付、気をつけて。
If you talk about the final closing, it's "Kiyotsu," "Kiyotsuke."
あ、そうそうそうそうそう。
Ah, that's right, that's right, that's right, that's right.
皆さん。
Everyone.
皆さん、お待たせいたしました。
Everyone, we're ready.
じゃあせーのでいくよ。
Then let's go with "Sei no."
はい。
"Hai."
せーの、起立！
"Sei no." "Kiritsu!"
気をつけて！
"Kiyotsuke!"
礼！
"Rei!"
礼、せーの。
"Rei," "Sei no."
キャプシャク モーメント！
"Kyahakusaku" "Moment!"
音の無い 真夜中過ぎに
Passing through the pitch-black, midnight hours,
思い出した 今日のミス
I remembered today's miss.
あぁ 嫌になっちゃうよな
Ah, I hate this kind of feeling.
笑えないときでも 笑い飛ばしてくれる
Even when I can't smile, you laugh it away for me,
そんな存在(きみ)
Such a presence (You).
そうさどんなときも 感じられるそばに
Yes, no matter when, I can feel you by my side.
目に見えぬ想い いつだって僕たちは
Unseen thoughts, whenever, we are...
キズナという魔法で 繋がっている
Connected by the magic called a bond.
やわらかなその笑顔を 胸に抱きしめて
Holding that soft smile close to my chest.
何 も 言わ ず 差し伸 べ ら れ た
Saying nothing, you reached out your hand,
その 手 は なんて あたたか いん だ ろ う
That hand was so warm.
いつか 同じ ように この 手 を 使え たら 嬉しい な
If I could use my hand the same way someday, how happy I'd be.
大事 な とき 照れて 言え ず じまい だから
At important times, I'm too shy to speak,
この 歌 に 乗せ て あぁ 本当に ありがとう
So I'll put it in this song. Ah, thank you so much!
気づか ぬ よう に そっと 見守っ て くれ た
So as not to be noticed, you gently watched over me,
さりげない その 優しさ を 僕 は 守り たい
I want to protect that unassuming kindness.
明日 は 雨 も あがり 七色 の 虹 が かかる
Tomorrow the rain will clear, and a seven-colored rainbow will appear.
僕 に は 見える
I can see it.
そう さ どんなときも 感じ られる そば に
Yes, no matter when, I can feel you by my side.
目に 見えぬ 想い そう やっ て 僕たち は
Unseen thoughts, that's how we...
大切な人 を 想い 繋がっ て
Think of someone dear and connect.
風 の 歌 も 空 の 色 も
The song of the wind, the color of the sky,
街 の 騒音(おと) も なにもかも
The noise of the streets, everything,
自分 なり の 構え で
In our own unique way,
キズナ という 魔法 を かけて 生き て く
Casting the magic called a bond, we live on.
誰も が そう 独り じゃ ない
No one is truly alone,
この 世界 の 中
In this world.
いこーよ！みんな、笑顔を探しにいこーよ！
Let's go, go! Everyone, let's go find smiles!
困り事から許されよー！
Troubles are forgiven!
空間・次元始まる！
Space-time scale, starting!
最大規模で行きたいの！
I want to go on a maximum scale!
キミもんちゃうん知ってよね？
Kimimon-chaun, do you get it too?
ね、どっち切符を手に入れよ？
Hey, which ticket should we get?
好調戦前もびっくり！
Koron-sen's and Sensen's moving!
キャスト追いつけない追い切り！
Can't catch up to the cast, I'll chase them!
変わっちゃう！
I won't change my mind!
ワイワイしちゃおう ほ〜ら
Let's get rowdy, hey...
Let’s go!
Let's go!
ニーハオ! 今日は 誰も浮かれチャイナ
Ni hao! Today, everyone gets carried away!
やあムチャだって ワクワクな ビートの祭典
Even if it's impossible, a thrilling beat festival!
超絶歓迎! 浮世 忘れチャイナ
Supreme welcome! Forget the mortal world!
だってここはアイヤイヤーー 桃源郷なり
Because this is Aiyaiya—a utopia!
ココロも笑顔も 重ねてイーエル
Layering hearts and smiles, ier!
元気満タン 準備は万端
Full of energy, preparations are ready!
古今東西 盛り上がれ!
Get hyped, past and present, east and west!
「ウォーアイニー!」 叫べば 幸福招来
Shout "Wo ai ni!" and summon happiness!
すごい瞬間を 味わいたい
I want to taste this amazing moment!
Wow Wow あなたの本気を頂戴
Wow Wow, I'll take your best!
でっかい壁なんて ここにはない
There are no huge walls here!
ライライ 来々 Alright! 躊躇なんてバイバイ
Lai lai, lai lai, Alright! Hesitation is bye-bye!
ライライ 来々 Alright! いっせーのでハイ!!
Lai lai, lai lai, Alright! Ready, set, high!
シェイシェイ! それじゃ さらにハジキチャイナ
Xie xie! Then let's pop even more!
ささるビート ノリノリな 猫もダンサー
Piercing beats, high-energy cat dancers!
点心爛漫! 夢は叶えチャイナ
Dim sum brilliant! Make your dreams come true!
ココロも笑顔も 重ねてイーエル
Layering hearts and smiles, ier!
元気満タン 準備は万端
Full of energy, preparations are ready!
古今東西 盛り上がれ!
Get hyped, past and present, east and west!
「ウォーアイニー!」 叫べば 幸福招来
Shout "Wo ai ni!" and summon happiness!
宣言しちゃいます!うちらトップ目指して走ります!
We declare it! We're running to reach the top!
(全力で)
(With all our might!)
人気出ちゃいます!?すぐにネットチケット高騰
We're getting popular!? Instant ticket price surge!
(急成長)
(Rapid growth!)
アイドルその一(笑顔全開)
Idol rule one: Smiles wide open!
アイドルその二(ファンを大事に)
Idol rule two: Treasure your fans!
アイドルその三(汗は勲章)
Idol rule three: Sweat is a medal!
愛されよう!
Let's be loved!
朝練で足がガクガクです
My legs are shaking from morning practice!
眠気まなこ猫の手借りたい
Sleepy-eyed, I want to borrow a cat's paw!
「毎日超ハード...」
"Every day is super hard..."
向いてないってアンチの言葉に泣きたくなる日も
On days when anti-fans' words make me want to cry,
周りのみんなに置いてかれる日も
and days when everyone leaves me behind,
(食いしばってしがみつきたい)
(I want to bite down and hold on!)
しんどい時でも頑張ってって言ってくれたから
Because you told me to do my best even when it's tough,
全身全霊声が届くまで歌ってみせるよ!
I'll sing with all my heart until my voice reaches you!
君からのエール!コール!マジで頑張っちゃいます!
Your cheers and calls! I'll really do my best!
(限界突破ー!)
(Breaking through limits!)
満員御礼!ヤバい!?どこも入場規制中!
House packed! Oh no!? Admission restricted everywhere!
(大成功!?)
(Huge success!?)
アイドルその四(背筋はピンと)
Idol rule four: Back straight!
アイドルその五(前髪キープ)
Idol rule five: Keep bangs in place!
アイドルその六(間食はダメ!)
Idol rule six: No snacking!
可愛くね
Stay cute!
仲良しの姉妹で 秘密ごとはなかった
As close sisters, we had no secrets
好きの人の話 いつか聞きたいかも
Maybe I want to hear about who you like someday
突然どうしたの?「ちらっ」
What's sudden? "Peek"
私たち仲良しだけど
Even though we're close besties
大人になるほどに秘密増やしていいの?
as we grow up, is it okay to have more secrets?
予算は? けいの関係? そうよから
What about budget? Relationship? Hey, Prince,
王子様 歳を全然違うしたけど
even if our ages are completely different,
いいの? 王子様 ブレイクして ほっぺすつけて
is it fine? Prince, break and touch cheeks,
ポーズ決めて アップしよ 大好きだよ 大好きだよ
strike a pose, upload it! I love you so much!
見つめ合って 可愛いね 身悶えなこと 得意なこと
Staring at each other, so cute! Writhing in agony, what I'm good at,
好みなこと それぞれじゃん 嫌いだよ 嫌いだよ
what I like, they're all different. I hate you, I hate you!
喧嘩しても ずっと一緒だよね
Even if we fight, we'll always be together, right?
仲良しの姉妹ですが お付き合いはしてます
We're close sisters, but we're dating
イメージ真逆でも ちゃんと仲良くしてね
Even if our images are total opposites, get along well
取られたくないから 少し連れて見てきけど
I don't want you taken away, so I took you along a bit
本当楽しそうで 私も嬉しくなった
You looked so happy, and it made me glad too
気になる人とか居ないの? お姉ちゃんに教えて
Is there someone you're interested in? Tell big sis
出会ってからの恋愛は禁止 今はダメ 夢のため
No romance since we met, not right now, for our dreams
君のため 半分にして 半分にして 泣き笑いも
For your sake, split it in half, crying, laughing,
明日も 大好きだよ 大好きだよ 見つめ合って
tomorrow too, I love you so much, staring at each other
可愛いね 出会ったこと 好きなこと 好みなこと
So cute! What we encountered, what we like, what we prefer,
それぞれじゃん 嫌いだよ 嫌いだよ 喧嘩しても
they're all different. I hate you, I hate you! Even if we fight,
ずっと一緒だよね 仲直りも きっとすぐできる
we'll always be together, right? We'll make up soon for sure
一つ屋根の下で 明日も騒ごう
Let's make noise together under one roof tomorrow too
ブレイクして ほっぺすつけて ポーズ決めて アップしよ
Break, touch cheeks, strike a pose, and upload it!
大好きだよ 大好きだよ 見つめ合って 可愛いね
I love you so much, staring at each other, so cute!
出会ったこと 好きなこと 好みなこと それぞれじゃん
What we encountered, what we like, what we prefer, they're different!
嫌いだよ 嫌いだよ 喧嘩しても ずっと一緒だよね
I hate you, I hate you! Even if we fight, we're together!
聞いてくれてありがとう! みんなありがとね!
Thank you for listening! Thank you everyone!
忘れていた目を閉じて 取り戻せ恋のうた
Closing my eyes to things forgotten, regaining our love song
青空に隠れている 手を伸ばしてももう一度
Hiding in the blue sky, reaching out once more
宣言しちゃいます!
Let's declare it!
うちラトップ目指して走りまーす!
We're aiming for the top and running!
人気出ちゃいます!?すぐにネットチケット高騰
Will we get popular!? Net tickets will skyrocket instantly!
アイドルその一 (笑顔全開)
Idol Rule 1: Big smiles!
アイドルその二 (ファンを大事に)
Idol Rule 2: Cherish the fans!
アイドルその三 (汗は勲章)
Idol Rule 3: Sweat is a medal!
愛されよ!
Be loved!
朝練で足がガクガクです
Morning practice has my legs shaking,
眠気まなこ猫の手借りたい
Sleepy-eyed, I want to borrow a cat's paw.
「毎日超ハード...」
"Every day is super hard..."
向いてないってアンチの言葉で泣きたくなる日も
Days when anti comments make me want to cry,
周りのみんなに置いてかれる日も
Days when everyone around leaves me behind,
しんどい時でも頑張ってって言ってくれたから
Even when it's tough, you told me to do my best, so
全身全霊声が届くまで歌ってみせるよ!
I'll sing until my voice reaches you with all my heart and soul!
君からのエール!コール!マジで頑張れちゃいます!
Your cheers and calls really make me want to try my best!
満員御礼!ヤバい!?どこも入場規制中!
Sold out! Oh no!? Admission restricted everywhere!
アイドルその四 (背筋はピンと)
Idol Rule 4: Stand straight and tall!
アイドルその五 (前髪キープ)
Idol Rule 5: Keep bangs neat!
アイドルその六 (間食はダメ!)
Idol Rule 6: No snacking!
可愛くね
Cute and neat!
「赤点連発イノコリかあ...」
"Failing tests and staying after school..."
「そこ私の席なんですけど...」
"That's my seat though..."
「占い最下位だー...」
"Fortune dead last..."
しんどい時でも頑張ってって言ってくれたから
Even when it's tough, you told me to do my best, so
全身全霊声が届くまで歌ってみせるよ!
I'll sing until my voice reaches you with all my heart and soul!
君の一番は誰?言わなくてもわかるよね?
Who is your number one? You know without me asking, right?
推し変厳禁!絶対!私だけしか見ちゃダメっ!
No switching oshi! Absolutely! You can only look at me!
アイドルその七 (いつもポジティブ)
Idol Rule 7: Always positive!
アイドルその八 (時にあざとく)
Idol Rule 8: Sometimes cunning!
アイドルその九 (挨拶マスト)
Idol Rule 9: Greetings are a must!
アイドルその十
Idol Rule 10!
アイドルその女王
The idol queen!
"ありがとう"
"Thank you!"
君からのエール!コール!マジで頑張れちゃいます!
Your cheers and calls really make me want to try my best!
満員御礼!ヤバい!?どこも入場規制中!
Sold out! Oh no!? Admission restricted everywhere!
まてまてお利口よ
Wait, wait, be good girls,
あの謎の男
That mysterious man,
君のその目隠せさせた目に刻めよ
Engrave it in those eyes of yours that were made to hide!
アイドル十ヶ条
The Ten Idol Commandments!
やっほー!みんなに一番注目してもらいたい!
Yahoo! I want everyone to pay attention to me the most!
ももすずねねです!
I'm Momosuzu Nene!
みんな堂々見守っていてくれたよね?僕のことだけ見てくれる?
You've been watching over me steadily, right? Will you only look at me?
巡り会えた運命の星
The star of destiny we met under,
私の闇に輝く星
Shining in my darkness.
積んで積んで何度も通って
Stacking and piling up, visiting again and again,
経済回せ推しを試練
Turn the economy, put your oshi to the test!
香水振った 大好き 手紙を出そう 大好き
Applied perfume, I love you, let's send a letter, I love you.
ヒールも履いて 返事待ってる 大好き
Worn heels too, waiting for a reply, I love you.
リラ ここ散らして 大好き
Lila, scatter here, I love you!
しんどい愛してるのファンだけど同じ人間は好きになっただけじゃ
It's tough, I love you, we're fans, but ordinary humans only fell in love,
誰かに向けた簡単にいつも
Easily directed at someone always,
しいとそして落ち込んで愛してるのファンだけど
Depressed and feeling down, even though I'm a fan who loves you,
普通の恋と変わらないわけじゃん
It's no different from ordinary love, right?
イベントあるしすぐ会えるよね
There are events so we can meet soon, right?
他のファンのファン様はほどほどにしてよね
Tone down the other fans, okay?
このままにもっと盛り上がっていくぞ
Let's keep getting more and more hyped just like this!
勘違い匂わせは嫌い
Misunderstandings and hinting are things I hate!
呟きすぎるやつは嫌い
People who tweet too much are annoying!
見すぐ見すぐバイトとは古手で
Seeing right through part-timers,
持って持ってネイルを白
Holding and painting my nails white,
星信を通てしいとしてね
Believing in the stars, treating me tenderly,
人気嬉しいけど
I'm happy for the popularity, but
愛してるのファンだけど全部知ってるし彼女みたいでしょ
It's tough, I love you, I'm a fan who knows everything and acts like your girlfriend, right?
辿りの相手今部調子気になって朝ちゃう
The person who arrived, in high spirits, worrying till morning.
愛してるのファンだけどファンのこっちゃないに見つかれたいの
I love you, I'm a fan, but I want to be found where fans aren't noticed!
秘密を守るし口は堅いし一番近くが言いって
Guarding secrets, tight-lipped, staying closest is best!
ずっと一緒じゃいましょう
Let's stay together forever!
ある日突然 穏やかな日々 変わっちゃったの
Suddenly, peaceful days changed completely,
こっち見ないで ヤダこっち見て ダメどうしよう
Don't look this way, no, look this way, oh no!
顔が良くて ありがとう 私が生きる
Thank you for being handsome, I'm alive because of you!
理由袋で ありがとう 世界はあなた
Thank you for being my reason, you are my world!
世界はあなた 中心に回ってる
Spinning around you at the center,
愛して
loving you!
いるの
I'm in love...
文句ある？
Got a problem with that?
まぁ、NENEはこんなにみんなのこと考えてるのに！
I mean, Nene thinks about everyone this much, yet!
あー、ペンライトの色が違う人がいるじゃん！
Hey, there are people with different glow stick colors!
みんな健康してますの？ 返事は？ せーの！
Is everyone healthy? What's your answer? Ready, go!
予想外の風速ロマンス
An unexpected wind speed romance,
規格外のラブ・ヘクトパスカル
an extraordinary love hectopascal!
渦巻く
Swirling...
媚薬の誘惑 どこまでさらわれちゃうのの
temptation of aphrodisiacs, how far will I be swept away?
やばいやばい
Oh no, oh no,
気づいて
notice me!
大好き メガ好き 明日はもっと好き
I love you, mega love you, tomorrow I'll love you even more!
一斉に舞う花吹雪 これが恋?! かの有名な
Blossoms dancing together, is this love?! As the famous saying goes,
こんなに全部染められちゃって
getting dyed completely like this—
最大級 桃色タイフーン
max-level, pink typhoon!
いつも同じ 電車に揺られて 行って帰って
Always rocked by the same train, going and returning,
だけど時々 アイス食べれば ご機嫌でした
but sometimes eating ice cream made me happy.
切なさなんて 知らなかったの
I didn't even know what heartbreak was.
雨やどり 不意打ちクランクイン 現れたハート・デストロイヤー
Taking shelter from rain, a surprise crank-in, a heart destroyer appears!
相合傘 反則ランデブー いったいいどうなっちゃうのの
Sharing an umbrella, a foul rendezvous—what on earth is happening to me?
ずるいずるい
So unfair, so unfair,
許して
forgive me!
警戒態勢 近すぎ注意報
Alert state, too close warning!
一瞬マジな顔したの あれがサイン?! かの王道な
You made a serious face for a second, was that a sign?! Following the royal road,
二人が無限で 無限が二人に
two people are infinite, infinity is in two people!
こんなに全部溶け合っちゃって
Melting together completely like this,
歴史的モーメント
a historical moment!
ちょっと待って！ねねは副会長だから！
Wait a minute! Nene is the vice president!
え？ねねはこの学校の…副会長！あなたは？
Eh? Nene is this school's... vice president! And you?
あなたは、この世の全ての愛道の、一員生なのだな。
You are a member of the path of all love in this world, a first-year student.
かわいい！副会長！
Cute! Vice president!
なんだか！かわいい！
Somehow! So cute!
かわいいのは 副会長なのだ！さっきの
The cute one is the vice president! That heart-skip just now—
めちゃくちゃかっ…かっこいいじゃねえ！可愛かったのだよ！
was so co—cool! But also so cute, you know!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
さすが副会長だったのだよ。
As expected of the vice president.
ま、じゃあ副会長がちょっと仕切らせてもらうけど。
Well then, I, the vice president, will take charge.
自己紹介 まずしてもらっていいかな？1年生の方から。
Can you first introduce yourself? Starting with the first-years.
あ、はい、分かりました。
Ah, yes, understood.
ええと、初めまして！愛道の1年生の姫森ルーナなのだよ！みなさんよろしくお願いしますいたします！
Um, nice to meet you! I'm Himemori Luna, a first-year student in the path of love! Thank you all so much!
のだらって言えばよかったのに！どうなのだらって！
You should've said "nodara"! Like, "how nodara!"
いや、まだ1年生なんでちょっと副会長まだ、まだちょっとまだなれないんで。
Well, I'm still a first-year, so I'm still not quite used to being vice president yet.
ではどうぞ、副会長。
Well then, please, vice president.
じゃあ私、副会長みんなの心のおーっていう部分があるので、その後にエナジードリンクで返してください！
Then I, the vice president, have a "everyone's heart's..." part, so please reply with "energy drink!" after that!
もしや！ほらライブ！同期生！みんなの心のー！
By any chance! Look, live! Batchmates! Everyone's heart's—!
えなじードリンク！
Energy drink!
よきです！いいよいいよ！かわいい！
Excellent! That's good, good! So cute!
ねえ、ねねたちが一番可愛くない？今回の。
Hey, aren't Nene and company the cutest this time?
おいおいおいおいおい、ちょっと待ってほしなの！ちょっとさっきオカユと2人で歌った「アイドル」…
Hey hey hey, wait a second, nano! Earlier, the "Idol" that Okayu and I sang together...
アイドル10章も可愛かったのだよー！
Idol Chapter 10 was also so cute, nano!
もっと！もっと声出せるだろ！
More! You can give us more voice!
わらわらわらわらー！
Warawarawarawara!
どうよかったよ？本当よかった！可愛いだってよかったのだよ！
How was it? Really good! It was so cute, I'm so glad!
も、もうちょっと近づいて！おおー！
M-move a little closer! Ohh!
しょうがないのだな。
Can't be helped, nano.
ありがとう！もうちょっと近い？
Thank you! A little closer?
あ、ちょっと近い。ちょっと近い。ちょっと近すぎたのだな！
Ah, a bit too close. A bit too close. A bit too close, nano!
可愛いのだよ！
So cute, nano!
ええ、今日はね、なんと韓国インドネシアでライブビューイング中でもあるので、ぜひこちらのライブの感想を…
Um, today, you know, we're also live-viewing in Korea and Indonesia, so please share your thoughts on this live—
#ホロライブフェスEXPO24_DAY2でSNSにアップしてください！
please post on SNS with #HololiveFesEXPO24_DAY2!
どうぞよろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much!
よかったよー！
It was great!
え、じゃあ、ちょっとあのいつも（の）ペールライトはやっぱりやりたいよね！やりたいのだよ！やろうやろう！
Um, well then, we definitely want to do the usual pale light, right? We want to do it, nano! Let's do it, let's do it!
じゃあまず、初めはの、ピンクにみんなライトピンクに！
So first, starting with pink, everyone switch your lights to light pink!
ある日突然
Suddenly...
さあ みんなピンクにして～！
Now, everyone make it pink!
どれどれ どれどれ
Let's see, let's see...
かわいい！
So cute!
わあー！
Wow!
あれ？なんかいい？なんかウェーブとかしちゃうせ？
Huh? Is this good? Should we do a wave?
ウェーブ？うん！ウェーブ好き？
A wave? Yeah! Do you like waves?
よし！じゃあこっちからいくぞみんな！ウェーーーブ！
Alright, then let's start from this side! Waaave!
いけいけー！
Go, go!
次はオレンジに切り替えてー！
Next, switch to orange!
やったー！
Yay!
こっちから！ウェーーーブ！
From this side! Waaave!
めっちゃきれいなままだ！ありがとうー！
It's so beautiful! Thank you!
よーし！
Alright!
あれ、声出さないのもやろうぜ！
Hey, let's do one without shouting too!
オッケーオッケー！
Okay, okay!
声なし！声なし行くぞー！
No voice! Let's go without voices!
だーしー！
Louder!
よし！いくぞ！調子いー！
Alright! Let's go! Feeling great!
もっといけるだろー！
You can do better!
調子いー！みんな心は女子だろー！
Feeling great! Everyone's a girl at heart!
女子ー！女子ー！
Girls! Girls!
女子ー！
Girls!
とびっきりの女子ー！
The most special girls!
そして！そんなのに関係なく！
And regardless of all that!
全員ー！
Everyone!
サプライズだよー！
It's a surprise!
そして…ここからは…なんと…
And... from here... surprisingly...
ボリュームあっという間のお知らせなのだー！
A surprisingly quick announcement!
なのだー！なのでチケット買ってね！
Indeed! So please buy tickets!
運営からご訂正があり、韓国とインドネシアのライブビューイングはありません！
Management correction: no live viewings in Korea and Indonesia!
あ、すいません！なくしちゃいました！すいませんでしたー！
Ah, sorry! It was cancelled! We're sorry!
では、次の歌につなげていくならね！いこっか！
Well then, connecting to the next song! Shall we go?
せーの！キャプチャーザモーメント！
Ready, set! Capture the Moment!
無料パートは終了いたしました！ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free part has ended. Thank you for watching!